Rosa is a tool and system for handling
passwords, which makes it easy to be more
secure online.
Here's how it works.
The password you enter into websites when
you log in is made up of two halves.
Half your password is something you always
use.
The other half is something unique just for
that site.
You can trust Rosa with the unique half of
your password.
Let's say you're trying to set a password
for Amazon.
919Zap# is your half, which you have
memorized and never share with Rosa.
This is the half of your password, which
will be the same on all websites you use.
brightidea is the other half, which is
unique for Amazon.
You give Rosa that half of the password,
like this.
I'll store my password for Amazon by sending
a text message to Rosa, telling her I
want to store a password for Amazon.
I'm only telling Rosa half the password, the
unique part for each website, which is
brightidea in this case.
I'll never tell Rosa my half, the 919Zap#.
Also, notice I never set up a user account
or gave Rosa my username or any other
personal information.
She just knows my phone number because I'm
texting her.
Later I want to log into Amazon and need to
know the full password.
I ask Rosa for her half.
And to log into Amazon, I combine my half
919Zap# with what Rosa just told me.
brightidea.
And if you have a Mac and an iPhone, it's
even easier.
You can use iMessage on your Mac to type
your messages to Rosa using your keyboard.
Then when Rosa's half of the password is
texted back to me,
I can open it right on my computer and copy
it to the clipboard.
Have fun being more secure with Rosa.